Hasitha Bandara

Brewing Team Leader (Brewer) – Food and Beverage Industry

B.Sc. Graduate from University of Kelaniya Sri Lanka. Result-driven professional with having Lab R&D works, Food Production, Brewing and Management on the job experience (FMCG). Unionized staff management Skills with achieving all objectives and ensuring smooth operation.





hasitha.bandara@heineken.com hasitha_bandara@yahoo.com



(+9477) 677 4221 (+9476) 498 1966



F-01, Randiwela, Mawanella, Sri Lanaka



linkedin.com/mwlite/me

EXPERTISE

Laboratory Techniques

R&D Works

Quality Controlling

Food products Testing

Teamwork

Leadership

Stress tolerance

Filtration

Fermentation

Brewing Techniques

Automation

Brewmaxx SCADA

Decision making

Problem solving

Safe working practices

Man Management

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Brewing Team Leader (Senior Executive – Job Grade 09)

HEINEKEN Lanka Ltd.

December 2017 – Present



Mawathagama Brewery, Sri Lanka

- Maintain Safe, Healthy and Risk Free Working Environment on Shift
- Working with highly adaptive TPM Environment
- Apply Fundamental/Situational Knowledge of Brewing Plant, Equipment and Processes (Automated Brew House, Brewmaxx SCADA, Milling, Mash Filter, Centrifuge, Candle Filtration etc)
- Optimize Production performance and Team performance
- Facilitate team problem solving and decision making
- Training shop floor with Heineken Standards

Senior Executive (Production/Operation)

Hayleys Global Beverages (Pvt) Ltd.

February 2016 – December 2017 (02 Years)



<u>Soil Chemist</u>

Hayleys Plantation Services (Pvt) Ltd. December 2011 – February 2016 (04 Years)

The World Of Hayleys

Hatton Instant Tea Factory, Sri Lanka

Hatton KVPL Laboratory, Sri Lanka

PERSONAL PARTICULARS

Name in Full - Udarata Ralalage Hasitha Sandaruwan Bandara

Gender - MaleCivil status - Married

Date of birth - 15th December 1986 (32 Years Old)

National ID No - 863501458V
Nationality - Sri Lankan

School Attended - Pinnawala Central College (O/L and A/L)

TRAINING

 Agro Management Training in both the theoretical and practical aspects of Management of Plantation (Tea and Rubber). (09 Month Period) – Hayleys Group Plantations Services (Pvt) Ltd

Outward Bound Training programme. (Kelani Valley Plantations PLC)

Sustainable Land Management Practices Training programme. (Kelani Valley Plantations PLC)

ACADAMIC QUALIFICATIONS

B.Sc. General Degree at the University of Kelaniya. Index: EM/2007/005

Major Degree Contents - GPA = 2.42

Environmental Science

Industrial Chemistry

Zoology

Microbiology



Diploma in Quality Management at Sri Lanka Standard Institution (SLSI)

Index No: D/2010/A/005(Project pending)

Main Course content

- Basic concept of Quality and Standardization
- Human Resource Management (HRM)
- Statistical Process Control (SPC)
- System Approach for Quality

(ISO 9001: 2008 Standards, ISO Quality System Documentation, Quality Audit and ISO 19011 Standards, ISO 14001 Standards (EMS), Occupational Health and Safety Systems (OHSAS 18001), HACCP System / ISO 22000 FSMS, ISO 17025)

Total Productivity Management (TPM)

NON RELATED REFEREES

Prof. U. S. Amarasinghe

B.Sc. (Kelaniya), M.Sc. (Wales), PhD. (Ruhuna), D.Sc. (Bangor), FNASSLHGBL, Zoology Dptmnt, University of Kelaniya, Sri Lanka. Tel: (+9411) 290 3397

E-mail: zoousa@kln.ac.lk

Mr. Akila Dalpadadu

Deputy General Manager - HR and Process Development Hayleys Group, 400, Deans Road, Colombo 10. Sri Lanka.

Tel: (+94 51) 205 2433 Mob: (+94 77) 385 6700

E-mail: akila.dalpadadu@hgbl.hayleys.com

I do here by certify that the particulars given above are true and accurate to the best of my knowledge.

(Hasitha Bandara)

(01/01/2019)